<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<technical-decisions xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                     xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1">
    <bunch>
        <!--
         Replace entire f-elements from the base PP and update - f-components?
         Non-SFR changes made using XPATH expressions
        -->
        <applies-to max-inclusive="3.1" name="Mobile Device Fundamentals"/>

        <decision id='0346'>
            <notes>Revision of FMT_SMF_EXT.2 in MDF PP</notes>
            <change xpath=".//f-element[@id='fmt_smf_ext.2.1']" mode="replace">
                <f-element id="fmt_smf_ext.2.1">

                    <title>The
                        <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
                        shall offer
                        <selectables>
                            <selectable>wipe of protected data</selectable>
                            <selectable>wipe of sensitive data</selectable>
                            <selectable>remove Enterprise applications</selectable>
                            <selectable>remove all device-stored Enterprise resource data</selectable>
                            <selectable>remove Enterprise secondary authentication data</selectable>
                            <selectable>
                                <assignable>list other available remediation actions</assignable>
                            </selectable>
                        </selectables>
                        upon un-enrollment and
                        <selectables>
                            <selectable>
                                <assignable>other administrator-configured triggers</assignable>
                            </selectable>
                            <selectable>no other triggers</selectable>
                        </selectables>
                        .
                    </title>
                    <note role="application">Un-enrollment may consist of removing the
                        <abbr linkend="MDM"/>
                        agent or removing the administrator’s policies. The functions in the selection are remediation
                        actions that
                        <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                        provides (perhaps via APIs) to the administrator (perhaps via an
                        <abbr linkend="MDM"/>
                        agent) that are performed upon un-enrollment. “Enterprise applications” refers to applications
                        that are in the Enterprise application group. “Enterprise resource data” refers to all stored
                        Enterprise data and the separate resources that are available to the Enterprise application
                        group, per<linkref linkend="FDP_ACF_EXT.2.1"/>. If
                        <linkref linkend="FDP_ACF_EXT.2.1"/>
                        is included in the<abbr linkend="ST"/>, then "remove all device-stored Enterprise resource data"
                        must be selected, and is defined to be all resources selected in<linkref
                                linkend="FDP_ACF_EXT.2.1"/>. If
                        <linkref linkend="FIA_UAU_EXT.4.1"/>
                        is included in the<abbr linkend="ST"/>, then “remove Enterprise secondary authentication data”
                        must be selected. If
                        <linkref linkend="FIA_UAU_EXT.4.1"/>
                        is not included in the<abbr linkend="ST"/>, then “remove Enterprise secondary authentication
                        data” cannot be selected. Enterprise secondary authentication data only refers to any data
                        stored on the
                        <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
                        that is specifically used as part of a secondary authentication mechanism to authenticate access
                        to Enterprise applications and shared resources. Material that is used for the<abbr
                                linkend="TOE"/>’s primary authentication mechanism or other purposes not related to
                        authentication to or protection of Enterprise applications or shared resources should not be
                        removed.
                        <htm:br/>
                        <htm:br/>
                        Protected data is all non-TSF data, including all user or enterprise data. Some or all of this
                        data may be considered sensitive data as well. If “wipe of protected data” is selected it is
                        assumed that the sensitive data is wiped as well. However, if “wipe of sensitive data” is
                        selected, it does not imply that all non-TSF data (protected data) is wiped. If “wipe of
                        protected data” or “wipe of sensitive data” is selected the wipe shall be in accordance with
                        <linkref linkend="FCS_CKM_EXT.5.1"/>. Thus cryptographically wiping the device is an acceptable
                        remediation action.
                    </note>
                    <aactivity>
                        The evaluator shall verify that the
                        <abbr linkend="TSS"/>
                        describes all available remediation actions, when they are available for use, and any other
                        administrator-configured triggers. The evaluator shall verify that the
                        <abbr linkend="TSS"/>
                        describes how the remediation actions are provided to the administrator.
                        <htm:br/>
                        <htm:br/>
                        The evaluator shall use the test environment to iteratively configure the device to perform each
                        remediation action in the selection. The evaluator shall configure the remediation action per
                        how the
                        <abbr linkend="TSS"/>
                        states it is provided to the administrator. The test environment could be a
                        <abbr linkend="MDM"/>
                        agent application, but can also be an application with administrator access.
                    </aactivity>

                </f-element>
            </change>
        </decision>
    </bunch>
</technical-decisions>
